Laura Bermudez Garcia

Concord, CA 94521 | +1(206)972-9255 | laurabermudezg@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/laura-bermudez-garcia/

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with extensive application development experience; passionate about user-centered design with the ability to work as a liaison between technical and non-technical teams. Excellent experience gathering requirements and defining activities for improving software for business users.

CORE SKILLS & TECHNICAL SKILLS

Building Proof of Concepts, Graphing / Data Analysis, Live Data Visualizations, SCRUM Methodology, New Software Feature Development, **Technical:** JS, PHP/Hack, React, C/C++, C#, SQL, Jest E2E testing, .Net, HTML 5. MVC

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Facebook/Meta

Bay Area, CA 8/2020 - 11/2022

Served on 2 Teams: Messenger Kids Machine Learning Growth (6 months) and Facebook Product Accessibility team to help build a 0 to 1 tool to increase the efficiency and improve the robustness of the Accessibility Spec.

- Supported a company-wide accessibility metric that helped teams understand and prioritize
 accessibility issues. Built an initial proof of concept and doubled the capacity of our review program
 within 6 months.
- Advocated for tool health by setting up E2E tests; adapted the tooling available to track usability heuristics to be able to support reviews of VR/AR software and hardware

Stay home mom

Kirkland, WA 8/2014 - 08/2020

Kept up-to-date with technology through UW continuing education certificates while raising 6 children.

Software Engineer / Systems Analyst, Intel CorporationSan Jose, Costa Rica 08/2011 – 09/2014 Implemented graphing for data analysis, live data visualization, and information sharing for an internal tool that logs millions of data points across continents.

- Contributed to development of a factory construction project that consolidated 3 applications into one to improve customer's productivity and user experience.
- Winner of a Division Recognition Award (DRA).

Software Developer, Desert Development CompanySan Jose, Costa Rica 12/2009 – 07/2011

Developed a framework that significantly increased developers productivity.

Software Engineer, Western Union

San Jose, Costa Rica 04/2007 – 12/2009

Coordinated between teams to deliver new releases worldwide, gathering requirements from different regions to design and develop new features for a core business money transfer software distribution system.

 Received a quarterly award for excellent teamwork during a national Money Transfer software roll-out for US and Canada.

Software Engineer, Align Technology

San Jose, Costa Rica 02/2006-03/2007

Gathered requirements to develop new features for a C++/MFC 3D graphics application used to model orthodontic treatments that improved the company's productivity and knowledge management efforts.

EDUCATION / PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science | University of Costa Rica, San Jose, Costa Rica

- Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp: University of Washington, Seattle, WA. 2019
- Software Product Management Certificate: University of Washington, Bellevue, WA. 2017-2018